Guide to the Katherine V. W. Palmer and Ephraim Laurence Palmer memorabilia, 1918-1978
Palmer, Katherine V.W. and Ephraim Laurence memorabilia, 1918-1978
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Katherine V. W. Palmer and Ephraim Laurence Palmer memorabilia, 1918-1978, 1952-1978 (bulk)
4177
Katherine V. W. (Katherine Van Winkle) Palmer, 1895-
1.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, scrapbooks, directories, newsletters, clippings, minutes, reports, speeches, memorabilia, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bound volume of letters on the retirement of E. Laurence Palmer, 1952; scrapbook of letters on the retirement of Katherine V. W. Palmer from the Paleontological Research Institution, 1978; scrapbook on Katherine V. W. Palmer's trip to Japan, 1974; medal from the Paleontological Society. Also, Sigma Delta Epsilon materials, including correspondence, directories, newsletters, clippings, minutes, reports, speeches, and a history of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1921-1971; and four-page mimeographed outline of the development of the Nature Study program in the Department of Rural Education at Cornell, prepared by Professor E. Laurence Palmer. Also, letter to Dr. Palmer from Pvt. T.A. Baker, U.S. Marines, stationed in Nantes, France, Dec. 29, 1918, describing his experiences in the military service.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Bound volume of letters on the retirement of E. Laurence Palmer, 1952; scrapbook of letters on the retirement of Katherine V. W. Palmer from the Paleontological Research Institution, 1978; scrapbook on Katherine V. W. Palmer's trip to Japan, 1974; medal from the Paleontological Society. Also, Sigma Delta Epsilon materials, including correspondence, directories, newsletters, clippings, minutes, reports, speeches, and a history of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1921-1971; and four-page mimeographed outline of the development of the Nature Study program in the Department of Rural Education at Cornell, prepared by Professor E. Laurence Palmer. Also, letter to Dr. Palmer from Pvt. T.A. Baker, U.S. Marines, stationed in Nantes, France, Dec. 29, 1918, describing his experiences in the military service.
Original drawings by W. C. Baker and printing blocks for "Honne: The Spirit of the Chehalis, The Indian Interpretation of the Origin of the People and Animals as narrated by George Saunders," collected and arranged by Katherine Van Winkle Palmer, with a signed copy of the book and printing blocks.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Palmer, Katherine V. W. (Katherine Van Winkle), 1895-; Palmer, E. Laurence (Ephraim Laurence), b. 1888.; New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Rural Education.; Paleontological Research Institution (Ithaca, N.Y.); Sigma Delta Epsilon.
Subjects:
World War, 1914-1918.
Places:
Japan--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letters from students, associates, and friends by E. Laurence Palmer (retirement), 1952 (Box 1)
- Loose articles from letters of E.L. Palmer, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Loose articles from photo album - Japan excursion, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photo album (scrapbook) Japan excursion, 1974 (Box 1)
- Retirement letter album of Dr. Katherine Van Winkle Palmer, 1978 (Box 1)
- Loose items from letters of K.V.W. Palmer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1 medal - Katherine Palmer - Paleontological Society, 19 (Box 1)
- Sigma Delta Epsilon, Graduate Women in Science, Inc. (Box 2)
- Sigma Delta Epsilon News, 1940-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sigma Delta Epsilon News, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- S.D.E. Newsletter, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- S.D.E. Bulletin, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- S.D.E. correspondence, miscellaneous and business, 1935-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Newspaper clippings - S.D.E., 1945-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- A history of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1921-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Proposals for members-at-large, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Reports of S.D.E. committees, the National Secretary, and others, 1938-1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Directory of Members and Officers, 1924-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Chapter reports and business, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- S.D.E. national conventions; reports, minutes, and programs, 191923-1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Grand Chapter meetings, 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- National Council materials, 1928-1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- S.D.E. Alpha (Cornell) Chapter, 1932-1976 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
- Chapter memos and notices, 1937-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- S.D.E. speeches (and material for speeches), 1938-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- S.D.E. general information, 1919-1952 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Souvenir booklets from Initiation Banquets (Mr. and Mrs. Palmer); name tags and cards, 1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Letter from Pvt. T.A. Baker, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Original artwork and copy of "Honne: The Spirit of the Chehalis" by Katherine V. W. Palmer (Box 3)
- 7 small printing blocks used in "Honne", MU-2055 (Box 3)
- Mimeographed outline of development of Nature Study program, prepared by E.L. Palmer, no date (Box 17)